# RICARDO E. GÁLVEZ

— UI / UX Designer

I am a multidisciplinary designer with over fifteen years of experience in web design and development. I have built interfaces for small buisnesses and large cultural instituions alike.

I am seeking a position in User Interface, Experience or Visual Design

### CONTACT

#### **EMAIL**

ricardo.e.galvez@gmail.com

#### **PORTFOLIO**

ricardogalvez.design/portfolio

#### **PHONE**

267.918.6598

## SOFTWARE/TECH.

Figma Adobe CC Sketch HTML Sass / CSS JavaScript git

## **SKILLS**

User Interface Design
User Experience
Design Systems
Prototyping
Responsive Design
WCAG / Accessibility
Agile Development

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Fine Arts University of the Arts, Philadelphia, PA

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Senior UX / UI Designer 2022 — 2023

Pearson | Senior UX / UI Designer

Successfully designed and deployed new features improving workflows and notifications for *Bronte*, a course authoring platform for eText

Directed default component design and theming effort for *Bronte's* next-generation authoring environment

Successfully conducted comprehensive product design research and explorations for the experimental learning platform *Curriculex* 

# Web Designer & Developer 2018 —2022

Native Bound Unbound | Project Design & Technical Lead

Successfully defined technical requirements and established the branding and design systems.

Stablehouse.io | Freelance - UI Engineer

Successfully took the company's marketing site from Figma to production with Gatsby and Tailwind

Il Nido Seattle | Freelance - Project Lead

Directed and executed all aspects of the project; layout, visual design, logo design, and frontend development

# New York Public Library, 2015 – 2018

UI / Visual Design and Development | Design Lead

Successfully oversaw a diverse range of web and interface design projects from concept, prototype to production and accessibility

Conducted the experience and interface design for NYPL's Shared Collections, Staff Picks, and New Arrivals applications

**Design System Development** | Design Engineer

Owned and maintained a codebase built with Jekyll, SCSS, Javascript, and HTML Improved designer and developer experience by leveraging Gulp, git, and npm

Website Redesign | Lead Designer

Held a leadership role in the design and implementation of a new conceptual and visual language for the Library's main website

## PBS / THIRTEEN, New York Public TV, 2009 - 2015

UI / UX Design | Design Lead

Led the visual, UX and interface design for THIRTEEN Explore an iOS video on-demand app for IOS / iPad

Web Design | Designer - Individual Contributor

Produced production ready laytouts, typographic, color, multipage websites using Illustrator, CSS and HTML